Edward Twitchell Hall papers 1930-1979
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series I: Correspondence, 1930-1979
  - Somer, Robert; Spencer Memorial Church (see Glenesk, William). (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Spitz, René. (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Spivack, Mayer (see also Box 33/Folders 8-9). (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Stea, David. (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Stover, Leon. (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Struever, Carl and Stu. (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Summer Institute in Visual Anthropology. (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Tagiuri, Renato. (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Talks. (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Talks. 1968-- (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Thiel, Philip. (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Thompson, Bradbury. (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Thompson, J. Lawn. (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Towl, Andrew R. (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Toynbee, Veronica. (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Trager, George L. (see also Box 27/ Folder 7). (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Travel Itineraries. 1966-1974 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Tuve, Merle. (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Ulam, Stanislaw; U.S. Department of Commerce; University of California Department of Architecture. (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Useem, John and Ruth. (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Van Zandt, Howard. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Verde Valley School. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Watson, Jeanne/Lippitt, Ronald. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Watson, O. Michael (see also Box 33/ Folder 11); Wedge, Bryant M. (see GAP). (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Wekerle, Gerda (see also Box 37/Folder 5 and Box 49/Folder 13). (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Wenner-Gren Foundation for Anthropological Research. 1957-1963 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Wenner-Gren Foundation for Anthropological Research. 1964 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - White, Leslie A. (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Whitman, Winifred. (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Whyte, William Foote. (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Whyte, William H. (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Wilcox, Arthur T. (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Will, Otto A. (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Williams, Carroll and Joan/The Anthropological Film Center. (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Withers, Arnold; World Society for Ekistics (see Doxiadis, C.A.). (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Worth, Sol. (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Wright-Patterson Research Lab; Self Confrontation, etc. (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Wylie, Laurence. (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Yamashiro, Jane. (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Yates, Sidney R. (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Yonkers, E. Hubbard and Judy. (Box 16, Folder 21)
- Series II: Career, 1931-1978
  - Classroom and Field: Correspondence and Other Dated Items, School and Field (General). 1931-1942 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Classroom and Field: Notes, Papers, Exams, Drawings, Outlines, etc. 1931-1978 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Classroom and Field: Notes, Papers, Exams, Drawings, Outlines, etc. 1931-1978 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Classroom and Field: Notes, Papers, Exams, Drawings, Outlines, etc. 1931-1978 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Classroom and Field: Notes, Papers, Exams, Drawings, Outlines, etc. 1931-1978 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Classroom and Field: Transcripts, Class Work, Field Experience, etc. 1931-1978 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Classroom and Field: Maps, Photos Related to Field Trips. 1931-1978 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Classroom and Field: Miscellaneous, Voter Registration ( New Mexico) and Insurance for Camera Equipment. 1939, 1941 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - School Papers: American Archaeology. (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - School Papers: "The Evolution of the Alphabet." (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - School Papers: "Hogans." (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - School Papers: "Hohokam Pottery." (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - School Papers: "Implements of the Plains Indians." (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - School Papers: "Indian Pottery." (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - School Papers: "Indians of the Northwest Coast." (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - School Papers: "Methods of Ceramic Description Used by Workers in the Southwest Today." (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - School Papers: "Methods of Excavation in the Southwest." (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - School Papers: "Mogollon Pottery." (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - School Papers: Origin, Antiquity and Evolution of Man. (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - School Papers:"The Origin of Mogollon Culture." (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - School Papers: "Pottery of Ecuador and Peru." (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - School Papers: "Pottery of Mexico and Central America." (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - School Papers: "Pottery of the Costa Rican Highland Area." (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - School Papers: "A Preliminary Report of Plains Indians Pottery of Nebraska, Wyoming, Colorado and New Mexico. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - School Papers: Primitive Society. (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - School Papers: "Report: Archeological Field Trip, January 8, 1938." 1938 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - School Papers: "Report: Seminar 251 Field Trip, October 16 & 17, 1937." 1937 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - School Papers: "Thesis: How to Develop Community Leadership in a Small Rural or Village Community." (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Tree Ring Materials: Correspondence with Various Enclosures. 1937-1941 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Tree Ring Materials: Correspondence with Various Enclosures. 1942-- (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Tree Ring Materials: Specimen and Specimen Date Records. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Tree Ring Materials: Specimen and Specimen Date Records. (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Tree Ring Materials: Specimen and Specimen Date Records. (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Tree Ring Materials: Tree Ring Charts. (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Tree Ring Materials: Photos. (Box 20, Folder 7)
    Includes:
    "L310"
    "Outside of L310"
    "L316-12"
    "L401"
    "L1041"
    "L1042"
    "L1152"
    "L1298-1?"
    "L1405"
    "L2009"
    "L2251"
    "9? L2254"
    "L2276"
    "L2286"
    "L2379"
    "L3651"
    "L3653"
  - Tree Ring Materials: Keur Accounts. (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Tree Ring Materials: "Tree-Ring Dates from Navajo and Refugee Sites in the Gobernador and Cabezon Districts." After 1940 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Tree Ring Materials: Articles from Other Investigators, Maps. (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Tree Ring Materials: Notes, Record Forms, Charts, Photos, Final Exam: Archaeology 211 (Dendrochronology). May 14, 1937 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Southwestern Pottery: Photos- Shards, a-d; "Methods & Positives," e. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Southwestern Pottery: Charts, a-c. (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Southwestern Pottery: Southwestern Pottery: Charts, a-c. (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Southwestern Pottery: Pottery Sheets. (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Southwestern Pottery: Non Southwestern Traits in the Rosa Complex." (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Southwestern Pottery: "Report of Lassatter and Hall on Test I, Peris K, L, W, and X. University Ruin, Season of 1938." 1938 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Southwestern Pottery: Preliminary Classification of Prehistoric Southwestern Basketry, Gene Weltfish. 1932 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Southwestern Pottery: "Analyzing Patterned Behavior in Pottery Manufacturing," J.L. Washbon. 1970 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Southwestern Pottery: M.A. Thesis - Notes, Maps, Charts of Archaeological Survey of Walhall Glades, University of Arizona. Text of Thesis can be found at E9791 1938 26. (Reprint: Museum of Northern Arizona, Flagstaff, 1942. 1938 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Columbia University Governador Expedition: Correspondence with Ralph Linton and Others. 1940-1941 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Columbia University Governador Expedition: Correspondence with Ralph Linton and Others. 1942-1943 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Columbia University Governador Expedition: Objectives, Schedules, Maps, etc. 1941 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Columbia University Governador Expedition: Accounts. 1941 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Columbia University Governador Expedition: Bones from the Vicinity of Governador, New Mexico, Probably Basket Maker III, Barbara Lawrence. Correspondence, Text, First Draft, Final Carbon. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Ph.D. Dissertation: Correspondence with Columbia University Press. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Ph.D. Dissertation: Index. (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Ph.D. Dissertation: Early Stockaded Settlements in Governador, New Mexico: A Marginal Anasazi Developement from Basket Maker III to Pueblo I Times. Columbia University, Text (carbon). 1942 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Early Stockaded Settlements in Governador, New Mexico: A Marginal Anasazi Developement from Basket Maker III to Pueblo I Times.. Columbia University Published Version. 1944 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Peabody Museum Awatovi Expedition: Correspondence. 1942 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Peabody Museum Awatovi Expedition: Notes, Charts, Graphs, etc. 1942 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Peabody Museum Awatovi Expedition: The Dating of Awatovi..., Manuscript. 1942 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Peabody Museum Awatovi Expedition: The Dating of Awatovi..., Manuscript. 1942 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Peabody Museum Awatovi Expedition: The Dating of Awatovi..., Manuscript. 1942 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Peabody Museum Awatovi Expedition: The Dating of Awatovi..., Manuscript. 1942 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Peabody Museum Awatovi Expedition: The Dating of Awatovi..., Carbon. 1942 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Peabody Museum Awatovi Expedition: The Dating of Awatovi..., Manuscript. 1942 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Peabody Museum Awatovi Expedition: The Dating of Awatovi..., Manuscript. 1942 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Peabody Museum Awatovi Expedition: The Dating of Awatovi..., Manuscript. 1942 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Peabody Museum Awatovi Expedition: The Dating of Awatovi..., Manuscript. With Handwritten Corrections by J.O. Brew. 1942 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Peabody Museum Awatovi Expedition: The Dating of Awatovi..., Manuscript. Graphs, Notes, Photomicrographs. 1942 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Truk Islands: Correspondence, Orders, Travel Permits, Other Dated Materials. April 30, 1946 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Truk Islands: Correspondence, Orders, Travel Permits, Other Dated Materials. May 1, 1946 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Truk Islands: Logs. May 15, 1946-May 24, 1946 and June 10, 1946-August 3, 1946. (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Truk Islands: Maps and Charts. 1946 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Truk Islands: Maps and Charts. 1946 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Truk Islands: Miscellaneous: Labeled Drawings of Native Boats; Various Legal Agreements (1880-1890) in Turkese and in Translation. Document in Trukese; Newspaper Clipping. (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Truk Islands: Information on Trukese Families with Geneological Charts. 1946 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Truk Islands: Captioned Photos 1-20. 1946 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Truk Islands: Captioned Photos 21-41. 1946 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Truk Islands: Photos - People, a-e. 1946 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Truk Islands: Photos - People and Things, a; Mostly Things, b-e; Mostly Scenery, d-e. 1946 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Truk Islands: Photos - Notebooks, a1, a2, b. 1946 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Truk Islands: Offical Dated Reports. 1946 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Truk Islands: Research Reports and Notes. 1946 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Truk Islands: Draft Reports. 1946 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Truk Islands: The Economy of the Truk Islands: An Anthropological and Economic Survey. U.S. Commercial Company, Economic Survery, Honolulu. Carbon with Photos and Maps in Binder. 1946 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Washington, D.C.: Point Four Notebook - Alice Marriott. (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Washington, D.C.: Point Four Notebook - Alice Marriott. (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Washington, D.C.: Point Four Notebook - Charles Wagley. (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Washington, D.C.: Point Four Notebook - Joseph Greenberg. (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Washington, D.C.: Point Four Notebook - Morris E. Opler. (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Washington, D.C.: Point Four Notebook - "Assumptions of American Culture." (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Washington, D.C.: Trager, George L. Papers on Linguistics with Bernard Bloch, Henry Lee Smith, Jr.; Review of Trager Paper by Harold Whitehall. (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Washington, D.C.: Smith, Henry Lee, Jr., Papers and Reviews on Linguistics with Charles A. Ferguson, Robert E. Pittenger. (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Washington, D.C.: Whorf, Benjamin Lee, Papers on Linguistics. (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Washington, D.C.: Birdwhistell, Ray L, Papers on Kinesics. (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Washington, D.C.: Miscellaneous Papers on Linguistics. (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Washington, D.C.: Progress of Change, Paste-up of Booklet for Foreign Service Institute. (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Washington, D.C.: A Preliminary Report on the English Usage Test, Overseas Training and Research. 1957 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Washington, D.C.: The American University Language Center English Usage Test, Overseas Training and Research. 1960 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Washington, D.C.: ICA Participant, English Language Requirement Guide, Part I, Washington School of Psychiatry. 1960 (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Washington, D.C.: ICA Participant, English Language Requirement Guide, Part II, Washington School of Psychiatry. 1960 (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - NIMH Grants: Photos/Negatives, Numbered Series: a-F57, b-F58, c-F59, and d-F60. (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - NIMH Grants: Photos/Negatives, Numbered Series: a-I55, b-I56, c-F61, and d-unnumbered. (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - NIMH Grants: Photos/Negatives, Numbered Series: a-c Photos/Negatives, d Photos/Negatives/Slides. (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - NIMH Grants: Photos/Negatives, Numbered Series: a Photos/Negatives, b Photos/Negatives/Art Work, c-Negatives. (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - NIMH Grants: a-b Photos, c-d Photos/Negatives. (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - NIMH Grants: Photo Tracings: a Roll #0007; b Roll #008; c Roll #1; and d Roll #7. (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - NIMH Grants: Subject Numbers and Interaction Numbers, Permanent File Record. (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - NIMH Grants: Film Catalog and Film Related Materials. (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - NIMH Grants: Raters, Master File. (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - NIMH Grants: Subjects, Master File. (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - NIMH Grants: Subject and Interaction Numbers, Master File. (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - NIMH Grants: Permissions to Photograph Subjects. (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - NIMH Grants: Interview Questionaire Forms. (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - NIMH Grants: Interview Posture Analysis Forms. (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - NIMH Grants: Various Tests. (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - NIMH Grants: Proxemics Notation and Codings. (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - NIMH Grants: Inteview Forms A and B. (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - NIMH Grants: Transcriptions from Tapes. (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - NIMH Grants: Transcriptions from Tapes. (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - NIMH Grants: Interviews Comments, Notes. (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - NIMH Grants: Interviews, Comments: Marshall Williams. (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - NIMH Grants: Comments: Paul Byers. (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - NIMH Grants: Reports/Outlines of Project Work. (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - NIMH Grants: Research Notes. (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - NIMH Grants: Fortran Project, Proxemics Handbook. (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - NIMH Grants: Statistical Notes, Proxemics Handbook. (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - NIMH Grants: Miscellaneous Items. (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - NIMH Grants: Project: Study of Indian Intonation Patterns, Judy Yonkers. (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - NIMH Grants: Original Application/Proposal (see also Box 11/Folder 10 and Box 11/Folders 15-16). (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - NIMH Grants: "Contrastive Cultural Analysis of Micro-space." (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - NIMH Grants: "Social Space as Bio-Communication") MH 4166 Progress Report. (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - NIMH Grants: "Ethnic Use of Micro-space in Interpersonal Encounters" (MH 08045 Final Report). (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - NIMH Grants: "Nonverbal Interethnic Encounters in Urban Settings" (MH 19029 Final Report) pp. 1-66). (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - NIMH Grants: "Nonverbal Interethnic Encounters in Urban Settings" (MH 19029 Final Report) pp. 67-119. (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - NIMH Grants: "Nonverbal Interethnic Encounters in Urban Settings" (MH 19029 Final Report) Appendices A-D. (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - NIMH Grants: Preliminary Analysis of Computer Printout: Blacks, Whites, Puerto Ricans. (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - NIMH Grants: Computer Printout: Blacks, Whites, Puerto Ricans. (Box 30)
  - Other Proxemics Work: Study of Walking Behavior: "A Cultural Analysis of Waling: The First Step," Catharine Bell and Kathenne Ramseur. (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Other Proxemics Work: Study of Walking Behavior: "A Cultural Analysis of Waling: The First Step," Catharine Bell and Kathenne Ramseur. Notes and Data. (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Other Proxemics Work: Study of Walking Behavior: "A Cultural Analysis of Waling: The First Step," Catharine Bell and Kathenne Ramseur. Cartoons, 1-52. (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Other Proxemics Work: Study of Walking Behavior: "A Cultural Analysis of Waling: The First Step," Catharine Bell and Kathenne Ramseur. Cartoons, 53-104. (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Other Proxemics Work: Study of Walking Behavior: "A Cultural Analysis of Waling: The First Step," Catharine Bell and Kathenne Ramseur. Cartoons, 105-158. (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Other Proxemics Work: Study of Walking Behavior: "A Cultural Analysis of Waling: The First Step," Catharine Bell and Kathenne Ramseur. Cartoon Data Cards. (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Other Proxemics Work: Photos/Negatives, ETH. (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Other Proxemics Work: Photos/Negatives: Marshall Williams, Envelopes 1-3. 1967 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Other Proxemics Work: Photos/Negatives: Marshall Williams, Envelope 4. 1967 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Other Proxemics Work:Photos/Negatives: Marshall Williams, Envelopes 5-(6?)-7. 1967 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Other Proxemics Work: Photos/Negatives: ETH, File Box of Photos; Envelopes of Photos/Negatives; Three Boxes of Slides. (Box 32)
  - Other Proxemics Work: Paper by John R. Aiello and Donna E. Thompson. (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Other Proxemics Work: Paper (Draft with ETH Comments) by Irwin Altman and Anne Vinsel. (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Other Proxemics Work: Paper (Final) by Altman and Vinsel. (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Other Proxemics Work: Paper by P.J. Condor. (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Other Proxemics Work: Papers by Steven J. Finando. (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Other Proxemics Work: Paper by Robert F. Froston and Charles U. Larson. (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Other Proxemics Work: Paper by Carol L. Lassen. (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Other Proxemics Work: Papers by Mayer Spivack. (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Other Proxemics Work: Papers by Mayer Spivack. (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Other Proxemics Work: Paper by Helen B. Schwartzman. (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Other Proxemics Work: Papers (with ETH Notes) by O. Michael Watson. (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Other Proxemics Work: Papers from Man-Environment Systems. July 1970 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Other Proxemics Work: Dissertation by Alton J. De Long. (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Other Proxemics Work: Dissertation by Alton J. De Long. (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - Other Proxemics Work: Dissertation by Jack W. Simmons, Jr. (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Other Proxemics Work: Course Outline by George C. Klein. (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Other Proxemics Work: Course Outline by George C. Klein. (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Other Proxemics Work: Course Outline by George C. Klein. (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Other Proxemics Work: "Manual for Teaching Physics Based on Silent Language, Gerald Holton. (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Other Proxemics Work: Grant Proposals by Albert E. Scheflen and Samuel E. Casselberry. (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Northwestern University/Santa Fe, New Mexico: Correspondence, Papers-Donald C. Johnson. 1970-1972 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Northwestern University/Santa Fe, New Mexico: Correspondence, Field Notes, Papers - Gladys Levis-Matichek. 1971-1972 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Northwestern University/Santa Fe, New Mexico: Correspondence, Field Notes, Papers - Gladys Levis-Matichek. 1972-1974 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Northwestern University/Santa Fe, New Mexico: Seminar papers. 1971, 1974 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Northwestern University/Santa Fe, New Mexico: Correspondence, Papers - Kenneth and Cindy Baum. 1972 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Northwestern University/Santa Fe, New Mexico: Correspondence, Papers-Judy Fine. 1972 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Northwestern University/Santa Fe, New Mexico: A Comparative Investigation of Dominant Dyadism, John Scow. 1972 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Northwestern University/Santa Fe, New Mexico: The Game of Life. 1972 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Northwestern University/Santa Fe, New Mexico: Notes, Reports-Lane Ittleson. 1972-1973 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Northwestern University/Santa Fe, New Mexico: Miscellaneous Correspondence. (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Northwestern University/Santa Fe, New Mexico: Dissertation Proposal by James H. Heisler with Analysis and Commentary by Lane Ittleson. 1973 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Northwestern University/Santa Fe, New Mexico: Anthropology C-65 (Culture as Communication): Student Papers. 1973 (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - Northwestern University/Santa Fe, New Mexico: Dissertation Committee for Daniel A. Silverman. 1974 (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Northwestern University/Santa Fe, New Mexico: Seminar Papers of Cindy Peters Evans. 1975 (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - Northwestern University/Santa Fe, New Mexico: One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest; Further Papers. (Box 35, Folder 15)
  - Northwestern University/Santa Fe, New Mexico: Frederick Erickson, Dissertation: Discussion Behavior in the Black Ghetto and in White Suburbia: A Comparison of Language Style and of Inquiry Style. 1968 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Northwestern University/Santa Fe, New Mexico: Frederick Erickson, Dissertation: Discussion Behavior in the Black Ghetto and in White Suburbia: A Comparison of Language Style and of Inquiry Style. (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Northwestern University/Santa Fe, New Mexico: Houshang Mazaheri, Dissertation: An Investigation of Critical Requirements for Change Agents in Rural Iran. 1970 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Northwestern University/Santa Fe, New Mexico: Houshang Mazaheri, Dissertation: An Investigation of Critical Requirements for Change Agents in Rural Iran. 1970 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Northwestern University/Santa Fe, New Mexico: Helen Elisabeth Beale, Dissertation: "Real Pretending:" An Ethnography of Symbolic Play Communication. 1973 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Northwestern University/Santa Fe, New Mexico: Lawrence Edgar Fisher, Dissertation: The Imagery of Madness in Village Barbados. 1973 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Northwestern University/Santa Fe, New Mexico: Lawrence Edgar Fisher, Dissertation: The Imagery of Madness in Village Barbados. 1973 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Northwestern University/Santa Fe, New Mexico: Lawrence Edgar Fisher, Dissertation: The Imagery of Madness in Village Barbados. 1973 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Northwestern University/Santa Fe, New Mexico: John Schwartzmann, Dissertation: The American Family and Mental Illness: An Ethnography of Family Dysfunction. 1973 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Northwestern University/Santa Fe, New Mexico: John Schwartzmann, Dissertation: The American Family and Mental Illness: An Ethnography of Family Dysfunction. 1973 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Northwestern University/Santa Fe, New Mexico: John Schwartzmann, Dissertation: The American Family and Mental Illness: An Ethnography of Family Dysfunction. 1973 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Northwestern University/Santa Fe, New Mexico: Gerda R. Wekerle, Dissertation: Vertical Village: The Social World of an Urban Highrise Complex. 1973 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Northwestern University/Santa Fe, New Mexico: Juli Ellen Skansie, Dissertation: Death is for All: Death and Death Related Beliefs of Rural Spanish Americans. 1974 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Northwestern University/Santa Fe, New Mexico: Juli Ellen Skansie, Dissertation: Death is for All: Death and Death Related Beliefs of Rural Spanish Americans. 1974 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Northwestern University/Santa Fe, New Mexico: Gwen Louise Stern, Dissertation: Ethnic Identity and Community Action in El Barrio; also included a paper entitled "Human Ecology Area of Emphasis." 1976 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Northwestern University/Santa Fe, New Mexico: Gwen Louise Stern, Dissertation: Ethnic Identity and Community Action in El Barrio; also included a paper entitled "Human Ecology Area of Emphasis." 1976 (Box 38, Folder 2)